nintendolife.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Nintendo Life

**This privacy policy sets out how Nintendo Life uses and protects any information that you give us when you use this website.**

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 24th May, 2018.

## Personalised Data Settings

Below is the different ways we might use personal data on the site:

Personalised Ads Settings:

We would also like to use your browsing habits across Gamer Network sites in order to display ads that we believe are more relevant to your interests. Do you consent to this personalisation?

Yes No

Mormont Settings:

Mormont is an internal Gamer Network content recommendation system, we track what articles you read so we can recommend others. Do you consent to this personalisation?

Yes No

### Ad Tech Partners we use:

Gamer Network provide the advertising infrastructure on this website. Below is a list of all ad tech partners we work with, mainly through Google's DFP platform. When you opt-into 'Personalised Data' these partners may use your data to target ads depending on your browser history.

## Data we collect

If you decide to create an account and login, we collect the following information:

  * username (required)
  * email address & email preferences (required)
  * country / timezone (required)
  * profile description / forum signature (optional)
  * social media account information (optional)
  * gamer IDs (eg, PSN ID, Nintendo Network ID etc) (optional)
  * demographic information such as interests (optional)
  * answers to polls, surveys and questionnaire (optional)
  * game ratings (optional)
  * comments, posts and forum topics (optional)
  * liked comments/posts/articles (optional)

We also use  **Google Analytics**  to measure anonymous information about our all our visitors, such as visit frequency, duration and approximate geographical location. Both first-party cookies and third-party cookies from Google's DoubleClick ad network are also used to give us some broad demographic information about our visitors, such as age and interests, if they are available. Again, all of this information is completely anonymous and is used purely to help us align our content and advertising better with our audience.

You can opt out of being tracked with Google Analytics, please visit [Google's opt-out page](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

## What we do with the data we gather

We use this data to understand your needs as a user and provide you with a better, personalised service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests or location.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new content, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided, if you have opted into receive them.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the data we collect.

## How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks your browser permission to be placed on your device. The cookie then helps analyse web traffic or helps us identify you. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use Google Analytics to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

## Links to other websites

Our website will contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * Don't enter information you do not wish to share with us
  * Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for newsletter purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at [[email protected]](http://www.nintendolife.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ea8e8b9e8baa8486838c8fc4898587) or by updating your account preferences.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your explicit permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998 / General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to Nlife Ltd, Unit 18-19, Loughborough Technology Centre, LE11 3GE, United Kingdom or emails us [[email protected]](http://www.nintendolife.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#fb9f9a8f9abb9597929d9ed5989496).

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

## Removing your data

If you wish to delete your account, simply visit the account page (whilst logged in), click 'Delete Account' and follow the instructions. Your account, and all the data related to your account, will be deleted from our website within 24 hours. Your residual data may exist within our backup systems for up to 14 days.

## Competition Entries

Winners may be requested to take part in post competition promotional activity and we reserve the right to use the username, names and location (country) of winners, their photographs and audio and/or visual recordings of them in any publicity unless you specify otherwise.

Data relating to competition entrants will be retained for a reasonable period after the competition closes to assist us to operate competitions in a consistent manner and to deal with any queries. Data will then be removed from our systems and will not be used for marketing.

On the occasion that a third party, such as the product supplier, advertising agency or PR company who sponsor that competition is to provide prize(s) directly, your contact details and, if applicable mailing address, will be passed to the third party for the sole reason of delivering the prize.

## How to contact us

If you have any questions or concerns about our policy, please contact us by filling in our online [contact](http://www.nintendolife.com/contact) form.
